

#### Contact

40 rue turbil 69003 Lyon – FRANCE

<u>+33.6.78.87.56.20</u>

 $\square$ 

maxence@maxired.fr **y** @maxired

 $\mathbf{C}$ 

O

github.com/worldline

## Summary

I'm working as a Research and Development software engineer at Worldline.

My current mission is to build a microservices architecture in Node.JS.

As a team, our goal is to sustain or develop business though new technologies in datacenters.

Full stack developer, I am a polyglote programmer, particularly enthusiastic toward network oriented developments.

Linux and OpenSource softwares integration and development are my daily job.

#### Maxence Dalmais

JavaScript and Distributed System Architect at Worldline

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### JavaScript and distributed system architect

Worldline, Lyon, France - Since July 2014

- Building a micro-services framework based on <u>Pigato</u> and ZMQ
- · Creating tooling to change the way software is build
- Lead technical aspects
- Evangelisation of the project inside Worldline

## Lead robotic software developer on <u>Hiwr</u>

Worldline, Lyon, France - June 2013 - July 2014

- Full creation of an Open Source robot
- Strong emphasis on code modularity and performance
- Create several demonstrator for HR assistant, Home Automation or school assistant
- Win several Awards and help to acquire Connected Equipment companies as customers

### Full stack JS developer on Beekeeper

Atos Worldline, Lyon, France - January 2012 - June 2012

- Successfully build a full stack analytics dashboard solution in JS and MongoDB
- · Strong emphasis on flexibility, usability and performance
- · Agile developement in a team of 4 JS developers

## Node.JS developer on **Smartdata**

Atos Worldline, Lyon, France - January 2011 - December 2011

- Successfully build a vertical solution for Open Data in Node.JS
- · Rearchitect and rewrite the codebase 3 times
- Successfully scale thanks to mongoDB and ElasticSearch
- Agile developement in a team of 10 JS developers

# OTHER INTERESTS

## **Network oriented programming**

- Interest in Software Defined Network
- Developement of an Open source DHCP server in Node.JS
- Several developement involving design and implementation of LAN protocol

## Mobile and front-end Developement

- Involved in the creation of severals native android or IOS apps
- Experience in Responsible Web Design

# **CONFERENCES AND ASSOCIATION**

### Speaker at BlendWedMix

- Presentation of Riot.JS Scheduled for October 2015
- Connected Robots : be ready for the flood October 2014

### **Involved in LyonJS since 2012**

- Co-founder of the organization
- · Talk: Introduction to Riot.JS
- · Talk: Introduction to Web Workers

### Others community

- Active Members of Hckrs.io local hacker tribe
- Mentor at MediaLabSession Lyon 2015
- · Participation at Lyon Robotics Meetup
- Participation at fHacktory Lyon 2014

# **EDUCATION**

### **Telecommunication Engineer at INSA**

National Institute of Applied Sciences - Grandes écoles - Lyon, France - 3 years - from 2007 to 2010

Telecommunication, Network and Software development

### Master Degree student at KAIST

Exchange semester at Korean Advanced Institut of Science and Technology, Daejon, South Korea - Spring 2010

Advanced network, Distributed System, Game theory, Management for Innovation

#### **Telecommunication and Network Technician**

2 years technical degree (IUT) in University Joseph Fourrier, Grenoble, France

Software development, network analysis and configuration

## LANGUAGES

• French: Native Language

English : Professional working proficiencyGerman : Limited working proficiency

# EXPERIENCE OUTSIDE FRANCE

- Exchange Semester in South Korea
- Summer Internship in Karlshurhe, Germany
- Personals travels in USA, India, Australia and across Europa